Dr Paddy Tobias

About / Contact / Download resume / GitHub / References

About Me

Hi! I am the eResearch Analyst employed by Intersect Australia, based at Deakin University, Melbourne. I have been in this role for almost three years, two and half of which was based at the University of New England, Armidale (NSW). I moved to Armidale from Melbourne in 2010 for PhD in the inter-disciplinary field of peace and conflict studies, and I now find myself back in Melbourne. My PhD focused on the socio-cultural impacts of democratisation in Timor-Leste.

Read more about me here...

Current Position

eResearch Analyst, Deakin University - Intersect Australia

2018-ongoing

I am currently based at Deakin University, Burwood, reporting to the Director of the eResearch team, Dr Christopher McAvaney. My role is to service researchers at the Burwood campus, including providing data analytics, statistical support and training to researchers. Part of my role also includes providing strategic support to the university and faculties in the area of digital research.

▶ Click to see a selection of activities

Selected other experience

eResearch Analyst, University of New England - Intersect Australia

2016-2018

Previously based at UNE, reporting to the Deputy Vice Chancellor - Research (DVCR), Prof. Heiko Daniel. Whilst located in the Research Services Directorate, to carry out this role effectively, I worked collaboratively with the University Library and the IT Directorate, as well as the faculties.

▶ Click to see a selection of activities

Corporate Communications Officer, UNE

2015-2016

In this position I reported to the Office of the Vice Chancellor and spearheaded the Research Communications Strategy for the university as well as handling relationships with media outlets.

Unit Coordinator, Lecturer and Tutor, UNE

casual contracts, 2011-2015

I have held various short-term academic contracts in Sociology, Political Science and International Relations, Peace and Conflict Studies and Education, teaching face-to-face and online (Moodle).

Research Fellow, Institute of Conflict Transformation and Social Justice, Queen's University (Belfast)

2014

Lead Monitoring & Evaluation Consultant, Women's Empowerment and Access to Justice project in Timor-Leste, Search for Common Ground (Washington)

2013

Education

Ph.D, Cum laude. University of New England, 2010-2015

M.Data Science. University of New England, 2018-ongoing

B.International Relations, Distinction. Deakin University, 2007-2009

Other qualifications

Software Carpentry instructor accreditation, 2018

Skills

My proficiency in selected eResearch tools

R, RStudio, Shiny

Python 2 and 3

SQL (SQLite, Oracle, Postgres and MySQL) and database design

GitHub and version control

Bash, grep, sed

Qualtrics

Selected Professional Publications

- 2018 Surveying with Qualtrics. An introductory course for researchers.
- 2018 eventbriteR. A package for R that can call the Eventbrite API for event, order and user information.
- 2018 Join data check for Muscat. A Python program to ensure linking data exists between authority tables in Muscat.
- With N Reid, 2017, 'Improving the online profile of the Ngan'gi Language Collection', eResearch Australasia, Brisbane
- With T Reeson, 2017, 'Working towards the "end-to-end": Research Data Management Capability Development at UNE', eResearch Australasia, Brisbane

Academic Publications

- 2017, 'Truth and Reconciliation in Timor-Leste: Some reflections ten years on', in Reconciliation in conflict affected communities: Experiences and insights from the Asia-Pacific, Springer.
- With B Kovacs (eds.), 2016, 'Questioning "peace formation" and "peace infrastructure", a special edition of papers with The Peace and Conflict Review journal
- 2014, 'Modernisation in Timor Leste: The "Community" at Stake', in The Love of Education: Learning to Live Together, Bangkok: UNESCO, Asia-Pacific Programme of Educational Innovation for Development.
- 2014, 'Keeping Community: Traditional Culture and Implications for Maintaining Peace in Post-Conflict Society in Aileu, Timor Leste,' in H Ware, B Jenkins, M Branagan & D Subedi (eds), Cultivating Peace: Contexts, Practices and Multidimensional Models, Cambridge Scholar Publishing, Newcastle upon Tyne.
- 2012, 'Maintaining a Civic Nation: social cohesion in Timor Leste', M Leach, NC Mendes, AB. da Silva, B Boughton & A da Costa Ximenes (eds.), New Research in Timor Leste, Melbourne: Swinburne Press.

References

Prof Heiko Daniel **Deputy Vice Chancellor - Research**, University of New England hdaniel@une.edu.au | +612 6773 2080

Dr Jonathan Arthur **National Services Manager**, Intersect Australia jonathan@intersect.org.au | +614 309 690 502

paddytobias.github.io/resume

paddytobias@me.com

0403 328 864